Guide to the Nathaniel Gage Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Original Accession
  - CONFERENCES, ASSOCIATIONS, UNIVERSITIES, LABS (EXCLUDING NSSE)
    - Universities - State U. of N.Y. - Stony Brook., 1968 Jan 22 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Universities - U. of Cal., Berkeley - Center for R&D in Higher Education., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Universities - UCLA - Center for the Study of Evaluation of Instructional Programs., 1967-68 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Universities - UCLA - Symposium on "Problems in the Evaluation of Instruction"., 1967 Dec 13-15 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Universities - UCLA - School of Education., 1973 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Universities - U. of Cal., Riverside., 1971 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Universities - U. of Cal., Santa Barbara., 1967-76 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Universities - U. of Georgia, Athens - R&D Center in Educational Stimulation., 1967 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Universities - U. of Michigan - conference., 1970 Apr 3-4 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Universities - U. of Michigan - conference on Appraisal of College Teaching., 1958 Oct 13 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Universities - U. of Pittsburgh Learning R&D Center., 1967-71 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Universities - U. of Texas - R&D Center for Teacher Ed., 1967-68 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Universities - U. of Toledo (NLG Paper)., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Universities - U. of Toledo, Model Elementary Teacher Educ. Program., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Universities - U. of Wisconsin R&D Center for Learning & Re-education., 1966-70 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Upper Midwest Regional Educational Laboratory., 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Western Psychological Assn., 1964-69 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Western Psychological Assn., 1972, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - NSSE (NATIONAL SOCIETY FOR THE STUDY OF EDUCATION)
    - Board of Directors - Chairmanship of the Board., 1971 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Board of Directors - Board meeting., 1970 Feb 15 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Board of Directors - Board meeting., 1971 Feb 25-26 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors - Board meeting., 1971 Sep 17-18 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Board of Directors - General., 1972, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      Including Minutes.
    - Board of Directors - Room & travel arrangements and other business matters., 1969-73 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Dead or dormant proposals., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence., 1967-68 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence., 1968 Oct-1969 Jun (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - General., 1970 Feb-1971 Jan (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - General., 1972 Mar-1973 Mar (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - General., 1973 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Allen-Wagschal Proposals., 1969-70 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Comm. on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Business Matters., 1972-76 (Box 19, Folder 20)
      see also Box 19, F. 34& 35
    - Exploration correspondence., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Paperbacks, incl. Pygmalion Paperback., 1971-72 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Phi Delta Kappa Joint Comm. on Leadership., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Yearbook on Adolescence., 1972 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Yearbook - Behavior Modification in Education., 1969-73 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Yearbook on Classroom Management., 1976-77 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Yearbook on Communications and Education., 1969-73 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Yearbook on the Curriculum., 1970-72 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Yearbook on "The Elementary School in the U.S."., 1971-73 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Yearbook on Learning in Early Childhood., 1969-72 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Yearbook on Linguistics in School Programs., 1969 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Yearbook on Mathematics Education., 1970 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Yearbook on Philosophy & Educational Research., 1969-71 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods., 1971-75 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Correspondence., 1974-76 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Outlines, guidelines., 1975 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Introduction, Chapter I. (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter II, "The Learning Basis of Teaching Methods." (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter III, "Programmed & Computer-Assisted Instruction." (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter IV, "Instruction From Printed Materials". (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter V, "Programs for the Individual Student." (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - ChapterVI, "Tutoring". (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter VII, "The Discussion Method." (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter VIII, "Humanistic Methods." (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter IX, "Teaching With Simulations and Games." (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter X, "The Lecture Method." (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter XI, "Teaching With Television and Film." (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter XII, "Classroom Teaching, the Synthesis of Teaching Methods." (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Yearbook on Psychology of Teaching Methods - Chapter XIII, "The Teacher's Decision-Making." (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Yearbook on Teacher Education., 1974-75 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Yearbook on Teacher Education, Research materials. (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Yearbook on Teacher Education, Correspondence & miscellaneous material., 1971-73 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - PUBLISHERS & PUBLICATIONS
    - Requests to print NLG publications; miscellaneous correspondence re. publications., 1966-75 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Allyn & Bacon, Inc., 1967-71 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - American Heritage Dictionary., 1966-76 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - American Men & Women of Science., 1967-72 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts., 1966 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Behavior Today - the Human Sciences Newsletter., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - The Bobbs-Merrill Co., Inc., 1970-72 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - British Journal of Teacher Education., 1976 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Brooks/Cole Pub. Co., 1972 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Cal. Journal of Educational Research. (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Contemporary Psychology - I. Recommended reviewers (alphab. by author of book)., 1968-69 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Contemporary Psychology - II. Recommended reviewers., 1970-73 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Contemporary Psychology - III. Recommended reviewers., 1973 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - CRM Books - Educational Psychology Chapter., 1971 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Croft Educational Services., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Crowell, Thomas Y., Co., 1968 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Dodd & Mead Co., Inc., 1970 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Education Recaps., 1965-68 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Education USA., 1963-65 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Educational Psychologist., 1965-72 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Educational Psychology, Div. of (Div. 15, APA) - Newsletter., 1959-71 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - ERIC: Educational Resources Information Center., 1966-75 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Ginn & Co., 1960-61 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Harcourt, Brace & World., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Harpers: Remmers & Gage, Revised Edition., 1949-55 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Harpers: Remmers, Gage & Rummel Book., 1962-67 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Houghton-Mifflin Co., 1971 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Internat. Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences., 1965 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Jossey-Bass Inc., Pubs., 1974 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Journal of Abnormal & Social Psychology., 1958 Aug-1960 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Journal of Abnormal & Social Psychology., 1960 Sep-1964 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Journal of Applied Behavior Analysis., 1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Journal of Applied Behavior Science., 1964 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Journal of Consulting & Clinical Psychology., 1970 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Journal of Educational Psychology., 1963-68 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Journal of Educational Psychology., 1969-76 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Journal of Higher Education., 1962 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Journal of Personality., 1961-72 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Journal of Research in Mathematics Education., 1969-73 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - The Journal of Special Education., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Journal of Teacher Education., 1961-76 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Leaders in Education (4th Ed.)., 1970 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Learning (The Magazine for Creative Teaching)., 1972 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - The Library of Contemporary Education., 1971 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - The MacMillan Co., 1967 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - McGraw-Hill Pub. Co., 1970-73 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Mental Measurements Yearbook., 1963 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - F.E. Peacock Pubs., Inc., 1967-75 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1969 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Psychological Abstracts: Correspondence., 1947-52 (Box 21, Folder 30a)
    - Psychological Abstracts: Abstracts., 1945-52 (Box 21, Folder 30b)
    - Psychological Abstracts., 1966-72 (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Psychological Bulletin., 1968-70 (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Psychology Today., 1966 (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Readings in the Social Psychology of Education - Revision (Miles & Charters)., 1967-71 (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Review of Educational Research., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Science: Evaluations for articles to be published., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Science Research Associates., 1961-76 (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Second Handbook of Research on Teaching. Gage-Snow Chapter: "The Role of Theories and Models in Research & Teaching.", 1969-72 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - Selected Academic Readings., 1969 (Box 21, Folder 39)
    - Sociometry., 1955-61 (Box 21, Folder 40)
    - SPSSI: Handbook & Casebook for Practical Evaluators (Consulting Editor)., 1968-70 (Box 21, Folder 41)
    - SPSSI Newsletters., 1954-73 (Box 21, Folder 42)
    - SPSSI: Readings in the Social Psychology of Education., 1969-72 (Box 21, Folder 43)
      See also Box 21, F.34.
    - Teachers College Record., 1965 (Box 21, Folder 44)
    - Teaching - a publication of SCRDT., 1970-72 (Box 21, Folder 45)
    - Urban Education., 1964-65 (Box 21, Folder 46)
    - USAF Research Reviews., 1952-53 (Box 21, Folder 47)
    - Washington Reports: APA., 1968 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - MISCELLANEOUS MATERIAL
    - Consultancies., 1960-75 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Cronbach material., 1967 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Invitations., 1956-64 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Invitations., 1965 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Invitations., 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Invitations., 1967 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Invitations., 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Invitations., 1969-76 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Invitations declined., 1968-71 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Invitations declined., 1972-76 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1964-65 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Incl. corresp.
    - Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968 May-1969 Aug (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969 Sep-1970 Jun (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970 Jul-1971 Jul (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971 Aug-1972 Sep (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 Oct-1976 Oct (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Stationery of former jobs. (Box 22, Folder 19)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1983-019
  - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - China (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University of Hamburg (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Indiana University (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Indiana University of Pennsylvania (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Indonesia: Folder #4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Indonesia: Folder #3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kent State Paper, 1980 Jul (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kent State University, 1980 Jul 10-12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - University of Kerala (South India) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln University (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Macquarie University (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University of Maryland (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford University: Subcommittee on Evaluation and Improvement of Teaching, 1979 May-1981 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - F2. C-AAA Subcommittee on Eval. Of Teaching, 1973-74 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford University: Human Subjects (Sponsored Projects) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - STANFORD UNIVERSITY: Sponsored Projects Office (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stanford University: Stanford Center for Information Processing (SCIP) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Task Force on Sponsored Research Volume (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Stanford University: Undergraduate Courses Application (for 215/145) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SUSE: Committee on Academic Affairs (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - SUSE: Administrative Services Credential Program (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Advisees (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - SUSE: Committee to Consider Courtesy Professorial Appts. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Committee on Curriculum & Teacher Ed. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Committee on Educational Research (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - SUSE: Conference on Teaching. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - SUSE: Faculty Meetings (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - SUSE: Faculty-Staff Bulletin, 1978 Sep 22- (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Research Assistants and Teaching Assistants Information (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - SUSE: Job Performance Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - SUSE: Institute for Educators from Republic of China, 1981 Jul (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - SUSE: Instructional Leadership Program (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - SUSE: New Courses Offered (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - SUSE: Policy Memo Series (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - SUSE: R&D Admin Mtg., 1977 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - SUSE: Research on Teaching Discussion Group (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - SUSE: Retreat, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - SUSE: SIDEC (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Special Education Requirements Committee (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - School of Education: Teacher Corps (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Stanford University, 1972 Jan (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Stanford University: WYLBUR (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Stanford University: Undergraduate Research Opportunity Listing (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Student files and course materials, circa 1968-1983; Accession ARCH-1984-002 (Box 1-6)
  Student files restricted for 75 years.
- Reports and testimony, circa 1956-1964; Accession ARCH-1984-078 (Box 1-2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1986-108
  - Report of the Task Force on the Impact of the Research, Development and Field Activities of the Ontario Institute for Studies in Education: Working Papers (Box 1)
  - Report of the Task Force on the Impact of the Research, Development and Field Activities of the Ontario Institute for Studies in Education: Summary and Conclusions (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1987-080
  - American Psychologist (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reviews, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Australian Educational Researcher (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - BTSE (Beginning Teacher Evaluation Study), California Commission for Teacher Preparation and Licensing (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Behavioral and Brain Sciences (An International Journal of Current Research and Theory with Peer Commentary) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campus Report p. 12: "What do we know about Teaching Effectiveness?", 1984 Nov 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Childhood Education (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Communication Quarterly (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals: Contemporary Authors (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Contemporary Education: Journal of Reviews (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Current Contents (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Original "Current Contents" cards (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Curriculum Inquiry (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Educational Leadership (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Educational Psychologist (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Educational Research Quarterly (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Educational Researcher (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Elementary School Journal (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Harvard Education Letter (Publications) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Institute for Research on Teaching: Longman Monograph Series (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - International Encyclopedia of Education (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - International Journal of Education Research (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - International Review of Education (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Journal of Classroom Interaction (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - New York Times (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Notes and News, University of Michigan State (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Review of Educational Research (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Science Clippings, 5+7/1982, 221/1983, 1984-, 1982, 1983, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Science (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Texas Tech Journal of Education (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - ERIC Clearinghouse on Teacher Education: N.L. Gage's Writings (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Macmillan Publishing Co.: Handbook for Research on Teaching, Third ed. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Pergamon Press Ltd., (Non-TATE) (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pergamon Editorial (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Phaser Data Systems (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Phi Delta Kappan: General (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Phi Delta Kappa: Publications (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Phi Delta Kappa: Hard Gains in the Soft Sciences (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Phi Delta Kappa: Monograph, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Phi Delta Kappan: Teaching Effectiveness: Reviewing and Applying What We Know - short version of a longer paper (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - List of names of persons to whom "Hard Gains" was sent (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Transparencies from "Hard Gains" (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Random House (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Teachers College Press, Teachers College, Columbia University (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Scientific Basis of the Art of Teaching, German Edition (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Yachdov United Publishers (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - University of Aachen, Federal Rep. of Germany (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - University of Amsterdam (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - University of Arizona (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - University of Brazil, Fulbright Lectureship, 1985 Sep-Oct (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Universidade Federal Do Rio Grande Do Sul, Brasil (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Brigham Young University (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - University of California, Davis (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - State of Florida, Dept. of Education (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - University of Haifa (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Harvard University Press (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Fort Hays University (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Harvard Graduate School of Education (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - University of Houston, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - University of Illinois (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - The Johns Hopkins University (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - University of Kansas (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Table of Contents
    Project Purpose
    Methods
    Plan of operation
    Personnel
    Resources
    Impact
    Budget
    Appendices
    Preparation
    Presentation
    Handouts
    Forms
  - University of Leicester, England (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - University of Liege, Belgium (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - University of Malaya (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Michigan State University (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - University of Michigan, Ann Arbor (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Michigan State University, Notes and News (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - University of Montana (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - University of Montana, 1985 Jun (Box 1, Folder 72)
    University of Rio Grande del Sol, 1985 Oct: "'Research on Teaching", Short Course
  - State University of New York at Albany (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - New York University (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - (Universities) Ontario Council on Graduate Studies (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Baxter, Jill (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bectium, Leonard (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Berliner, David, 1967-84 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Berliner, David, 1985- (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cordelle, Maria (ELEWAR) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Clarti, Chris (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clift, Renee (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Coladarci, Theodore (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Codori, Carol (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Corno, Lyn (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cronin, Denis (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Dictison, W. Patrick (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Foat, Classie M. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fong, Bernadine (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Garza, Tere (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Giaconia, Rose (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Griffey, David (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hativa, Nina (student) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hedges, Larry (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Huh, Hyung Chul (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stieff, Melley (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Krasno, Richard (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Marshall, Patricia McGinn (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - McKnight, Philip C. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Miaro, Be-Rammaj, II (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Mitman, Alexis L. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Mohlmann, Georgea (Gigi) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Moore, Carol Ann (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Needels, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Needels, Margaret (Peggy) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - SUSE/SCROT: Peterson, Penelope L. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AERA & Invisible College, Washington, D.C., 1987 Apr (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Requests for N.L. Gage's AERA Paper (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - AERA & Invisible College, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AERA Symposium, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AERA Hotel Reservations and letters to individuals (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AERA Meeting, Invisible College Mtg., 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - AERA Meetings: Invisible College, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - AERA and Invisible College, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - AERA General, 1982- (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - AERA, Division B (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - AERA, Division G (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - AERA, Division I: Education in the Professions (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - AERA, Division J (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - AERA, Encyclopedia of Educational Research, 5th ed. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - AERA: Persons requesting N.L. Gage's paper "The Nature of Replication and the Implications for Research Synthesis", 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - AERA: SIG: Classroom Management (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - AERA: SIG: Educational Research: Its History, Philosophy and Ethics (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - AERA: Newsletter of the Special Interest Group on International Studies (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - AERA: SIG on Teacher Preparation Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - AERA: SIG: The study of Learning Environment (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - AERA: SIG: Survey Research in Education (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - AERA: SIG: Teacher Preparation Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - AERA: Archives of the History of AERA (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - AERA, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - AERA, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - American Educational Studies Association (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - American Federation of Teachers (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - American Institute of Research (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - APA, Thorndike Award for N.L. Gage, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - APA, 1983- (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Original paper and list of people waiting to receive Dr. Gage's 1978 APA paper "Paradigms Found: New Prospects for Educational Psychology" (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - APA, Div. 5, Div. on Evaluation and Measurement, 1978- (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - APA, Div. 8, (SPSP - Personality and Social Psychology) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - APA, Div. 15, (Educational Psychology), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Archives of the History of American Psychology (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Association of Teacher Education (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Australian Council for Educational Research (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Bay Area Teacher Education Seminar (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - California Association of Teacher Education (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Carnegie Corp, New York (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching (Box 3, Folder 43)